



# Cláudio Rodrigues

Date of birth: 27/08/1998 | **Nationality:** Portuguese, British | **Gender:** Male |

(+351) 964039199 | claudioduarterodrigues@gmail.com

claudio.duarte.98@live.com.pt | https://www.claudiodrodrigues.com/ |

https://www.facebook.com/claudio.duarte.01/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/cláudio-rodrigues-5263551a8/

https://github.com/claudiorodr

Estrada de Santa Clara 295 A, 9300-163, Câmara De Lobos, Portugal

About me:

I'm a computer science student from Portugal, I am 23 years old and I'm an enthusiast of technology, specially everything software related. I have developed several open-source projects, either in my course or free time, most of them are available on my GitHub page with their description. Here you'll find more information about me, expertise, projects, and people I've worked with. You can also use the contact form to send me a message, I'll try to respond as soon as possible.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

27/07/2018 - 20/08/2018 - Larvik, Norway

#### WAITER

Summer job at a family restaurant, involves the preparation of tables, serving food or beverages and taking payments.

Larvik, Norway

02/07/2019 - 01/08/2019 - Funchal, Portugal

#### MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER - M-ITI

Summer internship promoted by the Regional Department of Education and Sport, through the performance of functions in the area of Computer Engineering, at the Madeira Interactive Technologies Institute, in the periods from July 2nd to August 1st, 2019 in a total of 132 hours.

Professional, scientific and technical activities | https://www.m-iti.org

Caminho da Penteada, Polo Cientifico e Tecnologico da Madeira, floor -2, 9020-105, Funchal, Portugal

01/01/2020 - 31/03/2020 - Funchal, Portugal

## **MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER - ARDITI**

Collaboration with other members of an interdisciplinary team, including marine biologists from the Oceanic Observatory of Madeira, developing cross-platform mobile applications in order to collect and export dive data, for further analysis on migrations of marine species on the island of Madeira.

01/02/2021 - 28/02/2022 - Funchal, Portugal

# TECHNICAL RESEARCH ASSISTANT - MARE-MADEIRA

- Applied technical skills to design and implement synergies for the development of new technologies and methodologies in marine ecology and biogeography, with a special emphasis in insular ecosystems.
- Optimized a variety of laboratory protocols and experiments with the help of software automation tools.

• Organized and prioritize daily laboratory tasks to fulfill established research aims.

01/03/2021 - CURRENT - Funchal, Portugal

## FULL-STACK ENGINEER - ELGORITHM

- Build innovative online marketplace platform in the tourism sector.
- Remote collaborating in a small team with innovative ideas.
- Development of high-performance web application using React and Node.js.
- Involved in CI/CD pipeline automation processes for build and deploy.
- Performed bug fixes and code reviews.

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

14/09/2016 - 28/06/2019 - Rua Dos Ferreiros, Funchal, Portugal

# **BACHLOR'S DEGREE - University of Madeira**

- Operating Systems
- Object Oriented Programming
- Database Management Systems
- Calculation I
- Data Structure and Algorithms
- Theory and Fundamentals of Computing
- Computing Architecture
- Introduction to Electronics
- Mechanics and Waves
- Networks and Data Communication
- Digital systems
- Requirements Engineering

# Field(s) of study

Information and Communication Technologies

EQF level 6 | https://www.uma.pt/

26/09/2020 - CURRENT - Rua Dos Ferreiros, Funchal, Portugal

## MASTER'S DEGREE - Universidade da Madeira

- Distributed systems
- Network-centric applications
- Artificial Intelligence and Game Design
- Software Design and Implementation
- Software Architectures
- Ubiquitous computing
- Security in Communication Systems
- Decision Support Systems

**Thesis:** Exploiting IoT-enabled Inertial Sensores

EQF level 7 https://www.uma.pt/

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **PORTUGUESE** 

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	B2	B2	C1	B2
NORWEGIAN	A2	A1	A1	A1	A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

## DIGITAL SKILLS

Python | JavaScript | Git | NodeJS | Django | Linux | Laravel | RESTful Api | MySQL | React js | Next.js | React Native

## DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: A1
Driving Licence: B1
Driving Licence: B

# ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

# **Organization skills**

- Good control in planning and organizing tasks acquired in carrying out volunteering (MIUT).
- Good ability to detect and estimate errors, and learn from them.
- Good ability to manage and guide small teams acquired in carrying out various group work.
- Experience with working in small groups (2-3 people).

## COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

# **Communication and interpersonal skills**

- Good analytical and communication skills acquired through experience acquired as a waiter in Norway.
- Willing to teach and help colleagues with more difficulties.